你正在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一个秘密的系统
The government has a secret system--
一台7X24小时监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我之所以知道 是因为是我建造的
I know, because I built it.
我设计机器的目的是侦查恐怖主义活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
它看到了牵扯到普通人的暴力犯罪
Violent crimes involving ordinary people,
像你一样的普通人
people like you,
政府认为这些犯罪无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯行动  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力干预的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为被当局追捕  所以我们只能秘密地工作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
但如果你是被害者或者肇事者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码出现  我们将会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第23集
Person of Interest S01E23 720p HDTV x264
-= 本季结束 =-
2002年5月17日
让我猜猜 我的晚餐肯定又泡汤了吧
Let me guess, I have to cancel my dinner plans.
警探 我们共同的朋友需要帮忙
Our mutual friend needs help, detective.
他正在市中心
He's downtown.
我一处理完这里的事情马上过去
I'll be there as soon as I get finished here.
警探 我并不想冒犯 但这是紧急情况
I hate to be rude, but it's an emergency, detective.
我们现在就需要你的帮忙
We need you now.
Carter.
Carter
现在赶快跟我来
I need you to come with me now.
但我现在有些事情
But I have this thing--
你那事情无关紧要了
Not anymore, you haven't.
这一直是我信条
It's an article of faith for me
那就是所有的罪犯 无论多聪明
that all criminals, however clever,
最终都会露出马脚的
eventually trip themselves up.
你想跟我说说这究竟怎么回事么
You want to tell me what this is all about?
那个穿西装的男人
Man in the suit?
我们追踪到他了
We got him.
2012年5月15日 6:00
早上好 Finch
Morning, Finch.
Reese先生
Mr. Reese.
你这几天去干啥了
What have you been doing?
腐蚀Fusco警探的心智去了
Corrupting detective Fusco.
难道他在这方面还没登峰造极么
Does he really need any help in that regard?
我在鼓励他有点大志
I'm encouraging him to show ambition,
在HR里面争取升官进爵
to climb the HR ladder.
恐怕这得等一段时间了 我们有新的号码了
Afraid it'll have to wait. We got a new number.
Caroline Turing.
Caroline Turing
哦
Oh.
她比Fusco漂亮多咯
She's lot prettier than Fusco.
并且行事谨慎多了
And much more discreet.
她的网络资料被仔细整理过
Her online profile is carefully managed.
你认为她藏了些什么吗
Think she's got something to hide?
按我说 应该有很多东西
Many things, I would expect.
她是个心理医生
She's a psychologist.
根据我可以确定的信息
From what I can determine,
她主要负责高端客户
she specializes in the high-end clients,
那些始终行事谨慎的人
the sort who insist on discretion.
我会再挖深一点 你先去接近她
While I dig deeper, you get close to her,
看看能否找到威胁的潜在来源
see if you can work out where the threat is coming from.
Finch 可能她就是威胁
She could be the threat, Finch.
我确信你也能把那个查清楚的
I'm sure you'll work that out too.
已连接
- 下一个 - 不好意思
- next. - Sorry.
份量加倍的焦糖玛奇朵 谢谢
Double shot macchiato, please.
喂 Lionel
Yes, Lionel.
我觉得我就要跟HR的大佬们见面了
I think I'm about to meet a few of the big hitters from HR.
真为你高兴呢
I'm thrilled for you.
我以为你要过来呢
I thought you'd want to be there.
我们可以把这些混蛋一网打尽
We could take these bastards down.
机会会来的
All in good time.
喂 是我在这冲锋陷阵呢 好么
It's my balls in a vice here, all right?
再加上Carter老是给我凶神恶煞的眼神
Plus Carter keeps giving me the stink-eye.
如今我们得快点把这事了结
Now we need to wrap this thing up.
会的 Lionel 但是得我说行才行
And we will, Lionel, when I say so.
与此同时 我想你帮我查个人
Meantime, I want you to look into someone else.
Caroline Turing 正在给你发她的照片
Caroline Turing. Sending you a photograph.
等你找到有用信息 给我回电话
Get back to me when you got something.
你认为我没听懂你的话么
Do you think I'm not understanding you?
没错 我是这样想的
Yeah, I do.
你在给我暗示 牵着我走
Giving me signals, putting words in my mouth.
我现在很担心那些
And I'm concerned about the things
已经对你吐露过的事情
I've already confided in you.
我们不是说好不做笔记么
I thought we agreed no notes.
的确 额
We did. Um...
不好意思 职业习惯
Sorry, old habits.
我告诉你的那些事 如果被别人听到
The things I've told you, if anyone else heard them,
都会产生很大的麻烦 你懂吗
that could be a big problem, understand?
谁的麻烦 Hans
For whom, Hans?
- 是你还是我  - 我们两个都是
- You or me? - Both of us.
你现在懂了么
You understand me now?
Larsson议员
Councilman Larsson,
Romano警探 Lewis队长
detective Romano, Captain Lewis.
这是Fusco警探
This is Detective Fusco.
Fusco 我们听说你手指沾上点脏水了
We hear you got dirty fingers, Fusco.
手指么 我可听说他把他那猪鼻子都
Fingers? I heard he's got his snout buried
塞进脏槽里面了
in the damn trough.
市议会和地区的代理人
City Council and the district attorney
不能再容忍纽约警方的妨碍了
no longer tolerate any malfeasance by NYPD officers.
你有什么要辩解的吗
What do you got to say for yourself?
额 这个 我不知道
You know, I-I don't know, uh...
坐下来 反正是自家人
Here. No social niceties.
手提箱里面有什么
What's on the docket?
我们有一笔交易
We got a contract.
一个有钱人有麻烦 他想杀个人
Rich guy with a problem. He needs it to go away.
方式由你决定
Method is up to you.
速度是唯一的要求
Speed is the only stipulation.
你要雇些枪手了吗 Simmons
You gonna pick the shooter, Simmons?
我的手下随时准备着
My guys are all solid.
Fusco在警局里面可以干预凶杀案
Fusco here will run interference with homicide
以防会有麻烦
in case there's any questions.
如果我要去关照一个人
If I'm gonna look after somebody,
起码要有他的名字吧
I'm gonna need to know their names.
不 你不需要
No. You don't.
现在的问题是 这个富人值得信任么
Now the question is do we trust the rich guy?
我只信任他的钱 钱已经提存了
I trust his money. It's already in escrow.
这一小部分是用来报销开支的
Here is a down payment for expenses.
不好意思 但为了帮你
I'm sorry, but in order to help you,
我必须获得你的信任
I have to have your trust.
很明显 我现在没有得到
Clearly I don't.
我把你引荐给另一位心理医生
I'm referring you to another therapist.
你不想再治疗我了吗
You're firing me?
不 我现在是承认自己失败
No, I-- I'm admitting failure.
我自动请辞
I'm firing myself.
你有问题要解决
You have issues to resolve,
你需要一个能够自由倾诉的医生
and you need to be able to speak freely.
Finch 你有在听么
Finch, are you listening to this?
这听起来Turing小姐的病人都有点缠人
It seems some of Ms. Turing's patients are a little... Clingy.
我已经敞开心扉了
I've been open.
我躺着接受你的治疗了
I laid myself bare to you.
我是在帮你 请相信我
I'm helping you, believe me.
又怎么了
What now?
你以为我高兴跟你说话么
Yeah, nice to talk to you too.
我跟他们见过面了 HR的内部议会
I met them. The HR inner council.
那你去干什么了 握个手喝杯酒么
So what was it about, handshakes and single malts?
不是 说正经的
No, this was serious.
HR现在接受雇凶杀人的业务了
HR is going in the murder-for-hire business.
你知道目标吗
Do you know the target?
那还用说 那人你也知道的
Yeah, I know the target. You do too.
就是那个你叫我查的心理医生小姐
It's that lady shrink you asked me to look into.
他们48小时之内就要她的命
48 hours and she's dead.
恒温器会有一个活动检测摄像头
Thermostat has a motion detector camera.
它会捕捉到每一个来往于Turning小姐
It'll capture the face of any patient
办公室的病人的面庞
coming or going from Ms. Turing's office.
它应该可以立刻辨认出
Should be able to identify
那些更为显眼的人员
the more prominent ones in no time.
我猜就是其中一个 雇用HR去杀她灭口的
I'm guessing one of them hired HR to keep her quiet.
问题是
Question is...
究竟是哪一个 在我们找到他之前
Which one? Till we figure that out,
我将会尽可能跟紧Turing的
I'm going to want to stay as close to Turing as possible.
我同意
I agree.
是时候让你去治疗一下心理问题了 Reese先生
Time for you to work through some of your issues, Mr. Reese.
我的心理问题么
Issues?
告诉我 你从事什么行业 您贵姓
Tell me, what is it you do, Mr...
Rooney.
Rooney
我是个顾问 这个很复杂
I'm a-- a consultant. It's complicated.
也不是很重要
Not really important.
我可不敢保证
I'm not so sure.
我的病人有很多病因都与工作有关
I find business is often personal with my patients.
我听说你很谨慎 值得信赖
I was told I could count on your discretion.
我的客户都很注重隐私
My clients are private people.
我尊重这一点
I respect that,
而我会尽我所能 保护他们的隐私
and I will protect it at all cost.
这女人深得我心啊
Lady after my own heart.
那么是什么让你来寻求治疗呢
So what brings you to seek therapy?
你介意拉下窗帘么
You mind closing the blinds?
如果这能让你更舒适的话
If it makes you more comfortable.
不如来杯饮料吧
Would you care for something to drink?
水就可以了 谢谢
Water would be fine, thank you.
看来这是她的行程表
Looks like her schedule,
周二
QY 两小时会面
LS 90分钟会面
但只有她客户名字的首字母
but with only her clients' initials.
这位女士有够谨慎的
The lady is careful.
警探 查到议员Larsson的财务信息么
Detective, any luck with Councilman Larsson's finances?
他这个星期存了五十万
He signed a deposit at his bank this week
进他的账户
for $500,000.
Harthope银行存款单
对一个公务员来说 是笔极其可观的收入
Nice chunk of change for a public employee.
纽约市议会 议员Seth Larsson
查到它的来源么
We know where it came from?
一个提存账户在同一个支行
An escrow account held at that same institution
支出了一笔相同数目的款项
made a disbursement that day in the same amount.
将那个账户的跟单号码发给我
Send me the tracking number for the account.
从这开始我接手
I'll take it from here.
为什么会有一个形象健康的议员掺和进来
What is the fine councilman mixed up in here?
这是雇凶杀人 警探
Murder for hire, Detective.
HR扩大业务范围了
HR is branching out.
我们再联系吧
We'll be in touch.
跟我说说 你有什么期望
Tell me, what do you see as the goal?
额 期望吗
Uh, the goal?
对 对你这趟治疗的期望
The purpose for your visit?
你现在看起来有点焦虑
You seem a little agitated right now.
何以见得呢
Why would you say that?
肢体语言 要求拉下窗帘
Body language, closing the blinds.
你不喜欢窗户 对么
You don't like windows, do you?
你究竟害怕什么呢
What is it you're afraid of?
真有趣 我本打算问你同样的问题呢
That's funny, I was gonna ask you the same thing.
问我吗
Me?
你的桌子下面装有一个紧急按钮
You have a panic button installed under your desk.
那是最近装的么
Is that recent?
抑或是 你害怕的是个人
Or someone you're afraid of?
你观察力高度敏锐
You're highly observant,
甚至对身边四周的事物过度敏感
hypervigilant, aware of your surroundings.
你是在说我有妄想症
You're saying I'm paranoid.
你觉得我是这意思么
Is that what you think?
我想的可是另外的东西
I was thinking something else.
你是退役士兵么
Former military?
小心点回答 Reese先生
Tread carefully, Mr. Reese.
- 有这么明显么  - 是有那么点
- Is it that obvious?  - A little.
你走进来的动作
The way you walk into a room.
你选择对着门的座位
The way you sit facing the door.
你看事情的方式跟大多数人不一样 对么
You see the world differently than most, don't you?
威胁潜伏在四周
A threat around every corner.
告诉我 你是不是感觉到你需要保护别人
Tell me, do you feel the need to protect people?
去拯救他们
To save them?
小心你的用词
Choose your words wisely.
我们不能让任何人发现我们在做的事情
We can't have anyone discovering what it is we do.
Reese先生 我设法去查阅了
Mr. Reese, I managed to get a read
资助HR的那个提存账户
on that escrow account that's funding HR.
问题是究竟谁雇用了他们
Question is who hired them?
无法确定
Impossible to determine.
因为那些钱来自数以百计的支付地点
The money comes from dozens of points of payment,
众多国家
multiple countries.
账户的金额总是恒定在五百万刀
The balance on the account is $5,000,000.
这可真是相当牛逼的付薪日啊
That's a hell of a payday.
有人千方百计想杀Caroline Turing灭口
Someone with tremendous means wants Caroline Turing gone.
我找了一个老朋友 帮我们
I've enlisted the aid of an old friend to help us
查出是谁
figure out who.
她蛮漂亮的
She's cute.
你好 Zoe
Hello, Zoe.
真高兴听到你需要帮助
Good to hear you're getting some help,
但John 我不认为有活着的女人
but I don't think there's a woman out there alive
能够治疗你的内伤
that could fix you, John.
Caroline Turing 你熟悉么
Caroline Turing. You familiar?
不 但明显有所预谋的
No, but that's obviously by design.
除了酒保之外 男人一般会
Next to bartenders, men usually like to spill it
向女心理医生倾诉
to female shrinks.
这比跟他们的妻子倾诉容易得多
It's easier than talking to their wives.
这些男人看重私隐
These men value discretion.
你有认识她的病人么
You know any of her patients?
一些
A few.
令人印象深刻
Impressive lot.
我把范围缩小到3个病人身上
I've narrowed it down to three players.
Hans Friedrickson 那个威胁她的律师
Hans Friedrickson, the lawyer that threatened her.
他现在应该启程公干去了
Supposedly he's away on a business trip right now.
或者离开这里给自己造一个不在场证明
Or left town to give himself an alibi.
二号病人 一个叫Terrance Baxter的银行家
Patient number two, banker named Terrance Baxter.
谣言说他正因涉嫌庞氏骗局受调查
Rumor is he's being investigated for Ponzi scheme.
然后还有David Sarkesian
And there's David Sarkesian.
他是个表现突出的市公务员
He's a prominent city official.
据闻说他在跟他的实习生上床
Whispers are he's sleeping with his intern.
看来我们的心理医生正坐在
Looks like our shrink is sitting
一个充满秘密的火药桶上
on a powder keg of secrets.
如果你正确的处理这件事 就会很有利可图
Which could be lucrative, if you play your cards right.
或一旦失误 足以致命
Or deadly if you don't.
目标在市中心工作
Target works downtown.
一般晚上很迟才离开办公室
Leaves the office late most nights.
每晚的回家路线一致
Same path every night.
她走过8个街区
She walks eight blocks
到Fulton Street地铁站
to the Fulton Street subway station.
其中有一个延伸到Pearl Street的街区
That one block stretch on Pearl Street?
有一处黑暗的区域
That's the dark zone.
没有临街商店 极少行人 没有摄像头
No storefronts, low foot traffic, no cameras.
一旦她从那个街角转弯 就踏入雷区了
Once she turns that corner, she steps off the grid.
那就是你的机会 抢劫演变升级
That's your window. Robbery gone bad.
事主的钱包在Alphabet城的垃圾桶找到
Purse to be found in a dumpster in Alphabet City,
凶器永沉在东河里不被发现
murder weapon never to be recovered in the East River.
- 轻而易举  - 我们就位了
- Piece of cake.  - We're on.
正向你那边走过来
Heading your way.
医生 你好
Hello, doc.
John 我
John, I--
你在这干什么呢
What are you doing here?
今晚恐怕不是出行的好时候
It's probably not a good night for a walk.
听着 John 这
Look, John, this--
这样不好
This is not okay.
你跟踪我了么
Were you following me?
不如我帮你叫辆出租车
How about I call you a cab?
这就是在今天的治疗中 我说到的问题
This is what I was getting at in today's session.
你认为每一处都潜藏着危险
You think there's something lurking around every corner,
但实际上不是这样的 John
but there isn't, John.
这里没有夜魔
There's no Boogeyman here.
你不再在危险的海外了
You're not overseas anymore.
而这是我每晚回家的路线
And this is the way I go home every night.
我坐的地铁就在那边
My-- my subway stop's right up there.
这里没事的
It's-- It's okay.
我很安全
I'm safe.
回家吧
Go home.
- 睡好一点  - 好吧
- Try to get some sleep.  - Okay.
我明天再跟你谈 好么
I'll see you tomorrow, okay?
过来 走吧
Come on, let's go.
Fulton与Pearl街发生枪击案
Shots fired, Fulton Street and Pearl.
众多警员回应
Multiple units responding.
他们是什么人 为什么他们要对你开枪
Who are those men? Why did they shoot at you?
因为我护在你的前面了
'Cause I was standing in front of you.
他们想杀我吗
They want to kill me?
- 别这样  - 为什么
- Don't.  - Why?
那些追杀我们的人就是警察
The men who are after us are cops.
没有办法分辨他们是不是一伙的
No way to tell if he's working with them or not.
走吧
Come on.
是我 除掉那个精神科医生了吗
It's me.Did you take care of the shrink?
还没
Not yet.
别告诉我你们五个 还搞不定一个女人
Telling me five of you can't handle one woman?
有个人突然冲了出来
Some guy came out of nowhere fast.
朝Mandel两条腿都开了枪
He shot Mandel in both legs.
让我猜猜 高个西装男
Let me guess.Tall guy in a suit.
那个女人看见你们的脸了吗
Did the woman get a good look at any of you?
看见了
Yeah.
对你来说真是坏消息 伙计
That's bad news for you, my friend.
你要是处理不好这事 我们可不会冒险
You don't clean this up,we're not gonna take the risk
给你叛变的机会
you'll turn state's.
要么你杀了他们
You kill them...
要么我杀了你
Or I'll kill you.
我们在这干吗
What are we doing here?
我们需要一个藏身的地方 重新部署
We need a place to hide,to regroup.
你好 请给我一间房
Hello. A room, please.
我们仅剩下一间
The only room we have available
蜜月套房了
is the honeymoon suite
每晚3000美金
at $3,000 per night.
就拿那间
We'll take it.
周边有太多警察
Too many cops in the neighborhood.
我们得潜伏在酒店里一直到早上
We'll need to lay low in the hotel till morning.
正在为你寻找逃脱路线 Reese先生
Working on an escape route for you, Mr. Reese.
感激不尽
Appreciate it.
这里处境确实有点艰难
In a bit of a tough spot here.
很好 现在你又幻听了
Great, now you're hearing voices.
不准确 是个朋友
Not exactly.He's a friend.
一个足智多谋的朋友
A very resourceful friend.
让我猜猜 我的晚餐肯定又泡汤了吧
Let me guess, I have to cancel my dinner plans.
警探 我们共同的朋友需要帮忙
Our mutual friend needs help, detective.
他正在市中心
He's downtown.
我一处理完这里的事情马上过去
I'll be there as soon as I get finished here.
警探 我并不想冒犯 但这是紧急情况
I hate to be rude, but it's an emergency, detective.
我们现在就需要你的帮忙
We need you now.
Carter.
Carter
我要你跟我来 就现在
I need you to come with me now.
但我现在有些事情
But I have this thing--
你那事情无关紧要了
Not anymore, you haven't.
我不懂
I don't understand.
谁会想杀我
Who would want to kill me?
我还希望你能告诉我呢
I was hoping you could tell me that.
某个人有这个手段和财力
Someone with the means and the money
雇一队杀手来除掉你
to hire a team to get rid of you.
听上去像你的某个病人吗
Sound like any of your patients?
像 每个都是这样
Yeah.All of them.
想引走这帮人 唯一的办法
The only way to call off the dogs
就是找出他们的雇主
is to find out who hired them.
我 我想不出来
I-I can't think.
我动不了都
I can't move.
这肯定就是所谓惊慌的感觉吧
This must be what panic feels like.
对 吃点巧克力吧
Here, have some chocolate.
吃这个能产生肾上腺素类的效果吗
Will these help to produce an adrenaline response?
不能 但是它们很好吃
No, but they taste good.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
差不多就是我们都帮助人们
Let's just say we both help people cope
解决问题
with their problems.
只不过我更加倾向于直接行动
I'm just a little bit more,uh, hands-on.
我保证
I promise...
我会告诉你什么时候该惊慌的
I will tell you when it's time to panic.
Carter 这位是Sagan警探 来自纽约警局
Carter, this is Detective Sagan, NYPD.
你要给她展示一下
You want to give her a little demonstration
你的成果吗
of what you do?
这段录像是90分钟以前的
This footage is from 90 minutes ago.
我们收到了枪击的报告
We have reports of shots fired.
然后他带着这个年轻女人逃逸了
Then he fled with this young woman.
我们认为她是人质 之后就没有他们的行踪了
We think she's a hostage. We lost them after that.
但我们确定 他们仍在方圆六个街区之内
But we're confident they're still in this six-block radius.
而这恰好是全世界受监控最严密的六个街区
Which happens to be the most heavily surveilled six blocks
这是一次联邦搜捕行动
in the world.This is now a federal manhunt.
在这看到你真惊讶 Fusco
Surprised to see you here, Fusco.
你知道的 我喜欢呆在行动现场
You know me. I like to be where the action is.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
好一点了
Better.
我需要一些帮助 Finch
Need some help, Finch.
HR找到了我们的藏身地
HR just found us somehow.
离他们找到我们的房间 大概只有两三分钟
It's probably two, three minutes before they find our room.
所以不能下楼了
So going down probably isn't an option.
我在研究方案
I'll look into it.
Reese先生 我想我找到了些东西
Mr. Reese, I think I've found something.
楼顶原先的占有者
Previous occupant of the penthouse
最近因为偷税坐牢去了
recently went to jail for tax evasion,
国税部还没有扣押全部的资产
but the IRS hasn't yet seized everything.
重点呢 Harold
The point, Harold?
我知道你很擅长偷车
I know you're good at stealing cars.
你觉得直升机怎样
How do you feel about helicopters?
离我上次飞已经好一段时间了
It's been a while since I've flown.
可能有点手生
Might be a little rusty.
乐观地看 如果你忘了怎么飞
On the bright side,if you don't remember,
也不会摔太狠的
it'll be a short fall.
等一下 等一下 回去
Wait, wait, go back.
就是他们
That's them.
通知我们的人到那家酒店集合
Notify our men to converge on that hotel.
无疑冒犯 警探
Uh, all due respect, Detective.
不过纽约警局这次不用参与了
NYPD's gonna sit this one out.
- 派我们的小组过去  - 遵命长官
- Send in our teams.  - Yes, sir.
去楼梯 快
Stairs. Now.
你救我 是为了过去
You saving me, is this making up
没有救某人而做补偿吗
for someone you didn't save?
我以为已经不用再做治疗了
I thought we were done with therapy.
谈论你的问题能让我分心
Talking about your issues helps distract me.
谁说我有问题的
Who said I had issues?
那我就当是有了
I'll take that as a yes.
等一下
Wait.
- 好像是直升机  - 我们不就是为此来的吗
- Sounds like a helicopter. - Isn't that what we want?
是的 但我还没动手偷呢
Yeah, but I haven't stolen it yet.
跟我来 计划有变
Follow me. Change of plans.
你说你会告诉我什么时候该惊慌
You said you'd tell me when to panic.
我猜应该就是现在吧
I'm guessing now's the moment.
将酒店安保系统转至你处
Wheeling the hotel security system feeds to you
倒数3 2 1
in three, two, one.
每层楼都搜一遍 要抓活的
Sweep every floor. I want him alive.
那些是什么人
Who was that?
- FBI  - 他们也要杀我吗
- FBI. - They want to kill me too?
- 实际上他们是来抓我的  - 什么
- Actually, they're after me. - What?
Finch 我这需要点帮助
Finch, need a little help here.
在想办法
Working on it.
Reese先生 去这栋楼西北角
Mr. Reese, make your way to the freight elevator
那有一架货运电梯
at the northwest corner of the building.
一直往下坐到负4楼停车场
Take it down to parking sublevel four.
那里有个旧的服务通道
There's an old service tunnel.
它连着港口边的废弃污水处理厂
It leads out to the old water treatment plant
我会在那接你
at the seaport. I'll pick you up there.
好的
Okay.
他们在45街，急需你的帮助
停，往回走，立刻 ――Carter
我们走
let's go.
走 ――Carter
走
let's go.
我们已经把他们包围了 但是情况有点复杂
My men are closing in, but there's a complication.
FBI来了
The feds are here.
他们不是来找Turing的
They're not looking for Turing.
他们想抓那个射手 我们得干掉他们两个
They want the shooter. We're gonna take them both out.
我们能怎么干掉他们
How the hell are we gonna take them out
头上可有FBI在啊
with the feds on top of us?
我们有内线
We got a guy on the inside
会告诉我们他们的位置
that's going to feed us their location,
并且搞定监控录像
take care of the cameras.
FBI以为他在挟持Turing当人质
The feds think he's holding Turing hostage.
他是个特种部队出身的疯子
He's some kind of special forces wacko.
他会想尽办法逃脱
He'll do anything to resist capture.
家伙带了吗
Bring the gear?
够挖出一个前往天朝的洞了
Enough to blow a hole to China.
把他逼到角落 然后炸掉整层楼
We're gonna corner him and blow the whole floor.
搞得好像他炸的一样
Make it look like he did it.
我们去大闹一场吧
Let's go make a mess.
Morgan女士 找到雇佣HR
Ms. Morgan, any luck finding the person
去杀Turing的人了吗
who hired HR to kill Turing?
还没有呢 但是我追踪到了Hans Friedrickson的助手
Not yet, but I tracked down Hans Friedrickson's assistant.
发现他其实出差去了
Turns out he actually was away on a business trip.
那是谁在威胁Turing呢
Then who was the man threatening Turing?
就快找到了
About to find out.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
好啊 我们谈谈
Sure, we can talk.
我追踪了你的电话
I traced your cell phone.
然后发现一件事
And here's the thing, Hans.
你的手机注册在一个叫Jimmy White的流氓名下
Your cell phone is registered to a low-life named Jimmy White.
通过最低生活保障金 骗点小钱
Short-con operator, had a couple of stints in minimum security.
不过说真的 你装检察官
But I got to say,impersonating a prosecutor?
真是装的不怎么样
That's probably not your best play.
就是个临时工作啊
It was just a gig.
他们逼我假扮什么叫Hans的人
They forced me to pretend I was this Hans guy,
去威胁某个精神科医生
threaten some shrink.
谁逼你
Who forced you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我发誓真的不知道 都是用email联系我的
I swear I don't know.It was all over email.
他们
They were...
敲诈我
Blackmailing me.
他们什么都知道
They knew everything.
我们到电梯了 Finch
We made it to the elevator,Finch.
很高兴听到这个消息
Glad to hear it.
我到位时会通知你
I'll contact you when I'm in position.
Morgan女士
Ms. Morgan,
在寻找HR的雇主这件事上 我们有进展吗
are we any closer to identifying who hired HR?
没有 但有些事很不对劲
No, but something seems really off.
有人雇Hans去当Turing的病人
Someone paid Hans to become Turing's patient.
我正在去她的办公室
I'm going back to her office to see
看看能不能找到点别的线索
if I can dig up anything else.
还有 Harold
And, Harold,
万事小心
be careful.
我不希望我们共同的朋友发生任何事
I'd hate for anything to happen to our mutual friend.
听到说 他们在货运电梯里
Got word they're on the freight elevator.
你可以在25楼截住他们
You can cut them off on 25.
HR在25层，快出电梯 ――Carter
你在干什么
what are we doing?
他们按了下一层的电梯键
They hit the button on the floor below us.
是要杀你的那帮人
The guys who were trying to kill you
还是要杀我的那帮人
or the guys who were trying to kill me?
把火警安全面板打开
Open the fire safety panel.
想办法让线路短路 一直到超载灯亮起来
Try shorting the wires till the override light comes on.
然后我们就能避开下一层
Then we can bypass the floor below.
他们把电梯停在了26楼
They stopped the elevator at 26.
把家伙安到楼梯井里 除掉他们
Set your charges in the stairwell, and get rid of them.
行动
Move.
我觉得我该向你道歉
I think I owe you an apology.
怎么说
How do you figure?
我本来给你的诊断是妄想症
I diagnosed you as paranoid.
仅仅因为你有妄想症
Just because you're paranoid
不意味着他们就不会来杀你
doesn't mean they're not trying to kill you.
我找不到正确的线路
I can't find the right wire.
没有作用啊
It's not working.
找到了
Got him.
让小组守住27楼
Tell the teams to stage off 27.
通过楼梯井B进入26楼
Enter 26 through stairwell B.
遵命长官
Yes, sir.
FBI在27层 ――Carter
FBI逼近了
FBI's closing in.
- 你们在哪了  - 已经可以撤退了 老大
- Where are we at, guys?  - We are good to go, boss.
好的 听我的命令行动
All right, you move in on my mark.
来抓你了 ――Carter
没时间了
we're out of time.
躲在我背后 我会尽力拖住他们
Just stay behind me, and I'll hold them off as long as I can.
行动
Do it.
准备行动
Get ready to move.
他有武器 但我希望尽量抓活的
He's armed, but I want him taken alive, if possible.
懂了吗
Understood?
但我会给你命令的
But I'll give you the signal.
就等你的命令了 Simmons
On your count, Simmons.
Five...
情况紧急 Harold
In a bit of a bind, Harold.
Four...
希望你还留了点看家本事
Hope you've got some tricks left up your sleeve.
一两招吧
One or two.
Three...
Two...
行动 就现在
Move in, team, now.
上
Go.
- 你听见我说话了吗  - Simmons
- Do you hear me?  - Simmons?
小队 快行动
Team, move in.
小组 马上行动 你们要错过目标了
Team, move now,you're gonna lose them.
TM发生什么事了
The hell's going on?
长官 联系中断了
Uh, sir, comms are down.
- 哪条线的联系  - 所有的
- Which comms?  - All of them.
线路中断了
Line's dead.
找到了
Got it.
到底TM发生了什么
What the hell's happening?
Canal街以南的信号塔全都挂了
Uh, every cell tower south of Canal Street just went out.
为了预备紧急情况 控制信号设施
DHS had a failsafe in place to take control
系统本来设置了故障保险的
of the cell infrastructure in case of an emergency.
有人黑进去了
Someone hacked it.
这些信号塔属于限定权限设施
The towers are white-listed.
要用授权码才能使用的
Only authorized numbers can use them.
这样的话 就只有一个号码
In this case, only one number.
谁的号码
Whose number?
我相信你还能听见我说话 Reese先生
I trust you can still hear me,Mr. Reese?
我得说Harold
I have to say, Harold,
我们都一起工作这么长时间了
we've been working together for some time now,
你却总能给我惊喜
but you continue to surprise me.
彼此彼此 Reese先生
Likewise, Mr. Reese.
你现在应该有着相当大的优势
You should have something of a competitive advantage now.
快用有线联系行动小组啊 靠
Just get the team on a hard line now, damn it.
等下 这家伙在干什么
Wait, what's this guy doing?
好 我们现在就到那去
All right, we're going down there now.
行动
Let's move.
谢了 Carter
Thanks for the help, Carter.
有人把你的行踪透露给HR的手下
Someone's feeding HR intel about your whereabouts.
不过我会处理好的
I'm gonna take care of it though.
Pearl街上没有警察
There are no units on Pearl Street.
你们可以从那里偷偷出来
You can smuggle them out there.
怎么了 Carter
What the hell, Carter?
把手机举起来给我
Hang up the phone and hand it to me.
快点 出来
Come on, come out of there.
这是怎么了 是一种误会吧
What's this about? Some type of misunderstanding?
不 我什么都知道了
No, I understand things perfectly.
你为HR工作
You're working for HR.
- 你在和谁打电话  - 关你什么事
- Who were you talking to? - None of your business.
你TMD想干嘛
What the hell do you think you're doing?
HR 你在泄密给他们
HR. You're guiding them.
你就是他们的耳目
You're their eyes and ears.
听着 Carter
Listen, Carter.
我是在HR卧底的 不是为他们工作
I'm working undercover in HR, not for them.
那是联邦调查局吗 还是联邦劳工局 给我看看你的文件 Fusco
The feds? IAB? Show me some paperwork, Fusco.
不是这样的 和官方的人无关
It's nothing like that. Nothing official.
听着 我做错了一些事 一些大事
Listen, I made some mistakes. Some big ones.
但现在不同了
But things are different now.
我在帮助别人 你必须相信我
I'm helping people. You got to trust me.
我现在就要知道怎么回事
I want answers. Now.
- 是那个西装男  - 你说什么
- The guy in the suit. - What did you say?
是你以前追踪过的西装男
The guy in the suit, the one you've been chasing.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
Look, I know this is gonna sound crazy,
但他们知道谁遇到了困难
but they seem to know when people are in trouble.
然后他们就帮助别人 他和另一个人
And they help them. Him and another guy.
有的时候我也会参与
And me too sometimes.
你说的另一个人 描述一下
This other guy. Describe him.
他像一个教授 他带着眼镜
He's like a professor. He's got the glasses
讲话文绉绉的
and a high-dollar vocabulary.
你进来前我就在和他打电话
That's who I was talking to when you came in.
你得跟我解释清楚 Finch
You got some explaining to do, Finch.
你好 警探
Hello, Detectives.
我理解你此刻有着一些问题
I understand you'll have some questions,
但我们现在没有时间了
but we're somewhat short of time.
我正在前往市中心 去帮助我们的朋友
I'm heading downtown to help our friend.
我建议你们也赶快去
I suggest you do the same thing.
John此刻就需要你们的帮助
John will almost certainly need your help.
你个贱人
You son of a bitch.
如果你不是内鬼 那是谁
If you're not the mole, then who is?
我很清楚内鬼是谁
I know exactly who the mole is.
我认识HR里的所有人
I know everyone who's in HR.
等我们处理完这件事 就把HR处理掉
When we get done with this, we're gonna take them all down.
现在怎么办
What now?
这里是旧维修通道
Old service tunnel down here
我们可以从这里出去
we can take outside the perimeter.
我的朋友在那里接应
My friend's meeting us there.
稍等一下
Hold on a second.
Reese先生 我就位了
Mr. Reese, I'm in position.
出去之后是一个污水处理厂
This comes out to a water treatment plant
在河旁边
by the river.
一直走就能碰到我的朋友
Keep going till you find my friend.
- 再见了  - 我会拖延他们 快走
- Split up. - I'll hold them off. Go.
谢谢你 John
John, thank you.
Turing正在去你那里
Turing's on her way to you.
我想我可能要晚点过去了
And I think I'm gonna be a little held up.
等我把Turing小姐送到安全地点
I'll get Ms. Turing to safety,
我就回来找你 John
and I'll come back for you, John.
Harold Finch 是吗
Harold Finch, I presume.
你真难找啊 Harold
You're a hard man to find, Harold.
- 我不知道你是  - 得了吧
- I don't know who you-- - Save it.
你以前见过我 记得吗
We met before, remember?
Nathan说你是他的IT技术人员
Nathan introduced you as his IT guy.
他还真是轻描淡写
He always had a talent for understatement.
你想从我这里得到什么 Alicia
What do you want from me, Alicia?
没什么
Nothing complicated.
你创造了上帝
You created God.
而现在 你要帮我把它关掉
And now you're gonna help me shut it down.
好了 前进 前进
All right, go, go, go!
朋友 看上去你快要挂了
Looks like you're just about out of time, my friend.
只是快要而已
Just about.
快进来
Get in!
进车里去
Get to the car!
在Nathan死之前
Before Nathan died,
在你建造的机器杀死他之前
before your machine killed him,
我知道有些东西正在蚕食他
I could tell something was eating away at him,
所建立的道德体系
the ethics of what he was building.
我还以为他是在和自己对抗
I thought he was fighting with himself over it.
原来他在和你对抗
But he was fighting with you.
他知道的 不是吗
He knew, didn't he?
创造出强大的机器所带来的傲慢感
The hubris of creating something as powerful as the machine.
我现在就能感受到
I can feel it right now.
监视着我们 监听着我们
Watching us, listening to us.
我们在此无处可藏
There's no hiding from it.
我逃的太累了
I'm so tired of running.
我做错了一些事
I've made some mistakes.
但不包括建造机器这件事
But building the machine is not one of them.
你没有在逃避机器 Alicia
You haven't been running from the machine, Alicia,
机器也没有杀死Nathan
and the machine didn't kill Nathan.
你在逃避人们
You've been running from people.
逃避我们都信任的人
From people that you and I both trusted.
没错
You're right.
很幸运的是我先找到了你
And you're lucky I found you first.
为什么不告诉我们 我们都为你工作
Why didn't you tell us we were both working with you?
- 为了保护你们 - 保护我们吗
- To protect you. - Protect us?
你差点让我被杀了
You almost got me killed.
你不相信我们 我们怎能相信你呢
You can't trust us, how are we supposed to trust you?
信任是一件很复杂的事情 Lionel
Trust is complicated, Lionel.
比如说 我坐在一辆警车里
For example, I'm sitting in a police car
其中一个警察想谋杀我
with one cop who tried to murder me
另一个花了六个月想把我抓起来
and another who spent six months trying to lock me up.
所以你们应该能原谅我 没有一下子都告诉你们
So you'll forgive me if I take things one step at a time.
减速吧 Carter
Slow down, Carter.
减速吗 那两个人知道
Slow down? These two know
他们就要完蛋了
they're going down for life.
他们会杀掉所有妨碍他们的人
They'll kill anybody who gets in their way.
我来对付他们
I got this.
相信我
Trust me.
我们得选个时间一起庆祝一下
Well, we should all grab a drink together sometime.
我请客
My treat.
你知道那些不法之人会对你干什么吗
Do you have any idea what the wrong person would do to you
一旦他们发现了你有访问权限
if they knew you had access?
知道你能造出多大的混乱
What kind of chaos that could create?
定义一下 不法之人
Define "wrong person."
你花钱让腐败的警察
You were willing to pay corrupt police officers
杀一个无辜的女人 把我引出来
to target an innocent woman just to draw me out.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
那台机器 你知道它是怎么运行的
The machine, you know how it works.
无关的名单
The irrelevant list.
你知道一旦你让Turing陷入危险
You knew it would send us Turing's name
机器就会把她的号码给我
if you put her in danger.
无关的名单吗
Irrelevant list?
我不需要来引你出来
I didn't need to lure you out.
我跟踪了你几个星期了
I've been following you for weeks.
我觉得她永远没法闭上嘴巴
I thought she'd never shut up.
很高兴终于认识你了 Harold
So nice to finally meet you, Harold.
你可以叫我Root
You can call me Root.
你被陷害了 John
You were set up, John.
Turing不是你所想象的人
Turing isn't who we think she is.
- 你说什么 - 她的办公室
- What do you mean? - Her office,
她的一生 都是个假象
her life, it's all a mirage.
我看到了转账记录
I saw the escrow transfer.
她就是买通HR的人
She was the one who paid HR.
她让HR来杀她自己
She put the hit on herself.
Turing一定对你们了如指掌
Turing must've learned how you operate,
你们会在她遇到危险的时候出现
that you'd show up if her life was in danger.
她引诱你去找她
She was trying to lure you out into the open.
她不是在找我
She wasn't looking for me.
她是在找Finch
She was looking for him.
你自己雇佣的HR
You hired HR yourself.
你冒着生命危险来寻找我吗
You were willing to risk your own life to find me?
我参加过一次这样的企业培训
I did this corporate training thing once.
当时我是去绑架一个CEO的 但这是后话了
I was blackmailing the CEO, long story,
他们组织了一个叫做信任背摔的训练
but they did this exercise called the trust fall,
让你闭上眼睛 然后向后倒
where you close your eyes and fall...
等着别人来接住你
And wait for someone to catch you.
我知道你们会来接住我的
I knew you boys wouldn't let me down.
来吧 Harold
Come on, Harold.
我们有太多东西得一起聊聊了
We've got so much to talk about.
匿名邮件
他现在陷入危险了 因为他在为你工作
He's in danger now because he was working for you.
所以我需要你帮我把他找回来
So you're gonna help me get him back.
评价中
运作连续性受到破坏
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第23集
Person of Interest S01E23 720p HDTV x264
-= 本季结束 =-